Albert Yang

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

albertesyang@gmail.com 289 500 6886 https://albertyang.io

Biography

Albert is a University of
Toronto CS graduate with
nearly a half decade of
software development
experience building customerfacing production applications.
He has proven results in
doubling web traffic and
engagement on client
projects, spanning a variety of
different industries, with a total
6.5m+ organic monthly visits
across projects

Skills

Languages

TypeScript, Java, Python, C#, Groovy, MySQL

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Next.js, Astro, GraphQL, Adobe Experience Manager, Tailwind, Node

Tools & Platforms

Git, GitHub, Contentful, Jenkins, Vite, Storybook, Figma

EXPERIENCE____

Software Developer II, I, Associate | Konrad Group

SEP 2020 - AUG 2023, TORONTO, CA

- Delivered high-quality, robust production code, with proven results of doubling traffic and engagement for a diverse array of clients including Kia Canada, Cadillac Fairview, Marks & Spencer, Autozone, and more
- Collaborated seamlessly with design, product, developer and stakeholder teams to bring client creative concepts to life, reaching 6.5m+ in organic monthly traffic across total projects
- Tested and resolved accessibility issues on all projects, reaching Web
 Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.0+ AA compliancy across the
 board

Software Developer Intern | Magnet Forensics

JAN 2018 - DEC 2018, MAY 2019 - AUG 2019, OTTAWA & WATERLOO, CA

- Architected and implemented several data parsing features in Magnet
 Axiom used in forensic cases by 4000+ law enforcement and corporate
 customers worldwide, including the FBI, Department of Homeland
 Security, and LAPD
- Ported existing build jobs to Jenkins pipelines, facilitating dynamic stages, parallelism and better source control
- Reduced operational burden by creating internal dashboard features to identify anomalies and trends, allowing developers to quickly root-cause build failures and ensuring a safer production workflow

EDUCATION_

University of Toronto | Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (Honours), Double Minor in Math, Business

SEP 2015 - APR 2020, MISSISSAUGA, CA

Courses: Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Engineering, Databases, Intro to ML/AI, Full Stack Web Development, Mandarin

Activities: Ultimate Frisbee Team, Badminton Club, Campus Photography Team

BrainStation | Diploma, Full Stack Web Development

JUN - SEP 2020, TORONTO, CA

PROJECTS___

Fortnite2D | Contributor

JAN 2020 - MAR 2020, SCHOOL PROJECT

A Fortnite clone in 2D written in React. Play against other players with millisecond latency on a forest map using websockets, pick up guns, ammo, object collisions

RooBot | Contributor

MAY 2020 - AUG 2020. PERSONAL PROJECT

A Discord bot written in Javascript. Offers giphy support and fun embedded commands. Went from design to implementation within a week. Increased community engagement and overall member experience

React Pokedex | Sole-Contributor

AUG 2020, HACKATHON PROJECT

A modern day Pokedex written in React. Has since become a sandbox to explore new web tech. Uses React Hooks, Typescript, axios, carousel animations